Patrick McTaggart-Cowan fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Patrick McTaggart-Cowan fonds
1929 - 1998
F-65
Q100354192
3.71 m of textual records ca. 400 photographs 17 artifacts
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Financial assistance for the arrangement and description of the records and production of the finding aid was generously provided by James McTaggart-Cowan and the Office of the President (SFU).
McTaggart-Cowan, Patrick
Patrick McTaggart-Cowan was a distinguished meteorologist who served as the first president of SFU.
McTaggart-Cowan was born in Edinburgh on May 31, 1912 and immigrated with his family to Canada in 1913. The McTaggart-Cowan family settled in North Vancouver, British Columbia. Patrick McTaggart-Cowan attended the University of British Columbia, graduating with an honours degree in Mathematics and Physics in 1933. He proceeded to further studies at Oxford as a British Columbia Rhodes Scholar, receiving a Bachelor of Arts in Natural Science in 1936. In 1939 McTaggart-Cowan married Margaret Palmer, with whom he had two children: a daughter, Gillian, born in 1942; and a son, James Duncan, born in 1944. Patrick McTaggart-Cowan passed away in 1997 at the age of 85.
Patrick McTaggart-Cowan was well known in Canada as a meteorologist, scientist and educator. After Oxford, he joined the Meteorological Service of Canada. As officer in charge of the meteorological service in Newfoundland from 1937 to 1942, he pioneered weather services for the first transatlantic passenger flights. During W.W.II, McTaggart-Cowan was chief meteorologist for the RAF Ferry Command, and was responsible for forecasting weather conditions for delivery of airplanes from North America to Europe. McTaggart-Cowan's skill in forecasting won him the gratitude of hundreds of pilots ferrying planes across the Atlantic, and earned him membership as an Officer of the British Empire in 1944. From 1945 to 1963, McTaggart-Cowan worked for the Meteorological Service of Canada in Ontario, where he became the Director in 1959. In 1963, McTaggart-Cowan accepted the position as first president of Simon Fraser University, and moved back to British Columbia. He helped to guide construction of the University, oversaw the hiring of professional staff, and helped to set up the academic structure of the university which opened in 1965. In 1968, McTaggart-Cowan was asked to resign his position as President by the Board of Governors. McTaggart-Cowan went on to head the Science Council of Canada from 1968 until his retirement in 1975. While with the Science Council, he was appointed by the federal Minister of Transport to head the Task Force Operation Oil in 1970 to clean up the oil spill in Chedabucto Bay, Nova Scotia. After retirement, McTaggart-Cowan moved to his farm in Bracebridge, Ontario where he continued to take an active part in environmental and science policy issues, such as acid rain, water pollution, and science education. He also became a beekeeper.
Patrick Duncan McTaggart-Cowan was the recipient of a number of international medals and honours. His national contributions earned him 7 honourary doctorates from across Canada, including those from the University of British Columbia and from Simon Fraser University.
He was created an Officer of the Order of Canada in 1979. In addition, he received a Coronation Medal in 1953 and the Canada Centennial Medal in 1967. For further information, see autobiographical notes, F 65-1-0-1.
published
Full
Revised
Title based on provenance of the collection.
Fonds consists of records made, received, and collected by Patrick McTaggart-Cowan in both his personal and professional life. Records document McTaggart-Cowan's work in Newfoundland both before and during W.W.II, his time with the Meteorological Service of Canada, as President of Simon Fraser University, as head of the Science Council, as head of Task Force Operation Oil and his activities after he retired. Also includes personal records relating to family, education, friends, and personal interests.
Includes autobiographical records, correspondence, diaries, journals, scrapbooks, notepads, financial records, speeches, publications, photographs, and artifacts.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Photographic materials; Artefacts; Textual records; Environment
All accessions have been processed as of May 2006. No further accruals are expected.
The McTaggart-Cowan family retained custody of the fonds until 1998 when they donated it to the SFU Archives.
See the inventory for the Office of the President, F 27. Also see a set of three audio cassette interviews, Patrick McTaggart-Cowan by Robin Fisher, September 6, 1989.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Biographical records, 1929 - 1998; F-65-1; 16 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records documenting the life of Patrick McTaggart-Cowan. Includes autobiographical notes, curriculum vitae, biography, a 1929 high school annual, school notes, honourary degrees, certificates, interviews, and articles about McTaggart-Cowan.
  - Autobiographical notes, 1998; F-65-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Curriculum vitae and biography, 1952 - 1973; F-65-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
  - North Vancouver High School - annual, 1929; F-65-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
  - Class notes, 1929 - 1934; F-65-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
  - Honourary degrees, 1961 - 1976; F-65-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
  - Certificates, vol. 1, 1959 - 1988; F-65-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
  - Certificates, vol. 2, 1959 - 1988; F-65-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 65-20)
  - Interviews, 1949 - 1980; F-65-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
  - Articles about McTaggart-Cowan, 1947 - 1978; F-65-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 65-1)
  - Certificates (oversize), vol. 3, 1959 - 1988; F-65-1-0-0-10
  - Len Norris cartoons about McTaggart-Cowan, 1965; F-65-1-0-0-11
  - RAF Ferry Command signed photograph, 1945; F-65-1-0-0-12
  - The Story of No. 45 Group, Royal Air Force, 1945; F-65-1-0-0-13
- Correspondence, 1933 - 1997; F-65-2; 1.35 m of textual records
  Series consists of correspondence created and received by Patrick McTaggart-Cowan in both his personal and professional life. Includes records that reflect his student days at UBC and Oxford, his professional life from when he first joined the Meteorological Service to when he retired from the Science Council in 1975, and correspondence after his retirement. Also includes correspondence relating to a number of projects, events or interests with which McTaggart-Cowan was concerned.
  - General correspondence, 1933 - 1997; F-65-2-1; 61 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of general correspondence created or received by Patrick McTaggart-Cowan. Records document a wide range of activities, and concerns relevant to McTaggart-Cowan's personal and professional life.
    - Correspondence, 1933 - 1937; F-65-2-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-2)
    - Correspondence, 1937; F-65-2-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-2)
    - Correspondence, 1937 - 1938; F-65-2-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-2)
    - Correspondence, 1937 - 1939; F-65-2-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-2)
    - Correspondence, 1939; F-65-2-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-2)
    - Correspondence, 1940 - 1949; F-65-2-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 65-2)
    - Correspondence, 1951 - 1958; F-65-2-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 65-2)
    - Correspondence, 1961 - 1968; F-65-2-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence, 1964 - 1968; F-65-2-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1968; F-65-2-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1968; F-65-2-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1968 - 1970; F-65-2-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1968 - 1970; F-65-2-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence, 1969; F-65-2-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence, 1969 - 1974; F-65-2-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 65-3)
    - Correspondence 1/3, 1975; F-65-2-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 65-4)
    - Correspondence 2/3, 1975; F-65-2-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 65-4)
    - Correspondence 3/3, 1975; F-65-2-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 65-4)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1976 - 1977; F-65-2-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 65-4)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1976 - 1977; F-65-2-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 65-4)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1977; F-65-2-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 65-4)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1977; F-65-2-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 65-5)
    - Correspondence 1/3, 1979; F-65-2-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 65-5)
    - Correspondence 2/3, 1979; F-65-2-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 65-5)
    - Correspondence 3/3, 1979; F-65-2-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 65-5)
    - Correspondence, 1979 - 1982; F-65-2-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 65-5)
    - Correspondence 1/4, 1980 - 1981; F-65-2-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 65-5)
    - Correspondence 2/4, 1980 - 1981; F-65-2-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 65-5)
    - Correspondence 3/4, 1980 - 1981; F-65-2-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 65-6)
    - Correspondence 4/4, 1980 - 1981; F-65-2-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 65-6)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1981 - 1982; F-65-2-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 65-6)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1981 - 1982; F-65-2-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 65-6)
    - Correspondence, 1982 - 1983; F-65-2-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 65-6)
    - Correspondence, 1990 - 1997; F-65-2-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 65-6)
  - SFU correspondence, 1963 - 1992; F-65-2-2; 28 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of correspondence reflecting the relationship between McTaggart-Cowan and Simon Fraser University. Includes records that reflect his tenure as president, his resignation, the granting of an honourary degree in 1972, and his continued involvement with the university.
    - Correspondence - congratulations, 1963 - 1964; F-65-2-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-6)
    - Correspondence, 1965 - 1966; F-65-2-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence - invitations, etc. 1/2, 1965 - 1968; F-65-2-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence - invitations, etc. 2/2, 1965 - 1968; F-65-2-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence - Biology 300, 1967; F-65-2-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence 1/4, 1968; F-65-2-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
      Restricted in whole
    - Correspondence 2/4, 1968; F-65-2-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence 3/4, 1968; F-65-2-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence 4/4, 1968; F-65-2-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence - re resignation, 1968; F-65-2-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 65-7)
    - Correspondence since 31 May 1968 - A, B, C, D, F-65-2-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence since 31 May 1968 - E, F, G, H, F-65-2-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence since 31 May 1968 - I, J, K, L, F-65-2-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence since 31 May 1968 - M, N, O, P, F-65-2-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence since 31 May 1968 - Q, R, S, T, U, F-65-2-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence since 31 May 1968 - V, W, X, Y, Z, F-65-2-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence - re job search, 1968; F-65-2-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence - Ladner Downs (Lawyers), 1968 - 1971; F-65-2-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence - Ladner Downs, 1968 - 1975; F-65-2-2-0-18.1 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence, 1971 - 1973; F-65-2-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence with University Archivist, 1973 - 1975; F-65-2-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence, 1977 - 1982; F-65-2-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence - University Club, 1984; F-65-2-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Correspondence, 1984 - 1992; F-65-2-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Memorablia, 1965 - 1966; F-65-2-2-0-24 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - President's residence, 1966; F-65-2-2-0-25 (Archival box - standard 65-8)
    - Architectural plans, 1965; F-65-2-2-0-26
  - Subject correspondence, 1963 - 1991; F-65-2-3; 46 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of correspondence relating to specific subjects, such as acid rain and oil spills. Also includes correspondence relating to conferences attended by McTaggart-Cowan.
    - Correspondence - acid rain, 1980; F-65-2-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - acid rain, 1983 - 1986; F-65-2-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - Arctic Institute of North America, 1975 - 1979; F-65-2-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - Arctic Institute of North America Conference -- Beaufort Sea, 1979; F-65-2-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - Associate Committee on Scientific Criteria for Environmental Quality (ACSCEQ), 1977 - 1978; F-65-2-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - Associate Committee on Scientific Criteria for Environmental Quality (ACSCEQ), 1980 - 1984; F-65-2-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - Associate Committee on Scientific Criteria for Environmental Quality (ACSCEQ), 1990 - 1991; F-65-2-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - beekeeping, 1977 - 1985; F-65-2-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 65-9)
    - Correspondence - Boyd Moving and Storage, 1975 - 1976; F-65-2-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - Correspondence - Brookings Institute, 1976 - 1978; F-65-2-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - Correspondence - Canadian Marine and Domestic Oil Spill Contingency Plan, 1976; F-65-2-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - Correspondence - Canadian Meteorological and Oceanographic Society, 1981; F-65-2-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - No file (see Collections File for information), F-65-2-3-0-13
    - Correspondence - Environmental Studies, University of Toronto, 1975 - 1978; F-65-2-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - Correspondence - federal and provincial governments, 1977 - 1982; F-65-2-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - Correspondence - "Living with Climatic Change" Conference 1/2, 1975 - 1976; F-65-2-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - Correspondence - "Living with Climatic Change" Conference 2/2, 1975 - 1976; F-65-2-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 65-10)
    - Correspondence - Muskoka, 1981 - 1985; F-65-2-3-0-18 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Muskoka Parry Sound Beekeeper's Association, 1977 - 1979; F-65-2-3-0-19 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Muskoka River, 1974 - 1976; F-65-2-3-0-20 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Oil spills, 1977 - 1978; F-65-2-3-0-21 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Ontario Forestry Association, 1976 - 1982; F-65-2-3-0-22 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Ontario hydro, 1981; F-65-2-3-0-23 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Ontario Ministry of Natural Resources, 1983 - 1984; F-65-2-3-0-24 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Ontario Science Centre, 1975 - 1978; F-65-2-3-0-25 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Operation Oil, 1970; F-65-2-3-0-26 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - pesticides, 1977 - 1979; F-65-2-3-0-27 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Project oil, 1970; F-65-2-3-0-28 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Science Council, 1971; F-65-2-3-0-29 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Science Council, 1972; F-65-2-3-0-30 (Archival box - standard 65-11)
    - Correspondence - Science Council, 1975 - 1976; F-65-2-3-0-31 (Archival box - standard 65-12)
    - Correspondence - Science Council, 1976 - 1983; F-65-2-3-0-32 (Archival box - standard 65-12)
    - Correspondence - Scientific, Engineering, and Technological Community of Canada (SCITEC), 1975; F-65-2-3-0-33 (Archival box - standard 65-12)
    - Correspondence - Vancouver move, 1963 - 1964; F-65-2-3-0-34 (Archival box - standard 65-12)
    - Aluminum wiring controversy, 1976 - 1979; F-65-2-3-0-35 (Archival box - standard 65-12)
- Diaries, journals and scrapbooks, 1938 - 1975; F-65-3; 47 cm of textual records
  Series consists of diaries, journals, notepads, and appointment books that reflect McTaggart-Cowan's daily activities. Also includes one diary written by Margaret McTaggart-Cowan, and scrapbooks complied by her.
  - Journals, 1938 - 1942; F-65-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-12)
  - Personal notepads, 1963 - 1968; F-65-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-12)
  - Daily journal, 1964; F-65-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-13)
  - Scrapbook (Jan. 18 to June 30), 1964; F-65-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-13)
  - Scrapbook (July 1 to Oct. 29), 1964; F-65-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-13)
  - Scrapbook (Oct. 30 to Feb. 10), 1964 - 1965; F-65-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 65-13)
  - Daily journal, 1966; F-65-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 65-14)
  - Daily journal, 1967; F-65-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 65-14)
  - Daily journal, 1968; F-65-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 65-14)
  - Date book, 1969; F-65-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 65-14)
  - Daily journal, 1970; F-65-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 65-15)
  - Diary, 1971; F-65-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 65-15)
  - Daily journal, 1972; F-65-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 65-15)
  - Daily journal, 1973; F-65-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 65-15)
  - Daily journal, 1974; F-65-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 65-16)
  - Margaret McTaggart-Cowan's journal, 1974; F-65-3-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 65-16)
  - Daily journal, 1975; F-65-3-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 65-16)
- Financial records, 1932 - 1948; F-65-4; 10 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the personal finances of McTaggart-Cowan. Includes records that reflect income while serving in Newfoundland, household accounts, banking records, and purchases.
  - Personal accounts, 1932 - 1938; F-65-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-16)
  - Personal accounts, 1938; F-65-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-16)
  - Personal accounts, 1938 - 1939; F-65-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-16)
  - Personal accounts, 1940 - 1942; F-65-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-17)
  - Personal accounts, 1940 - 1948; F-65-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-17)
- Speeches and lectures, 1946 - 1996; F-65-5; 36 cm of textual records
  Series consists of speeches given by McTaggart-Cowan on a number of topics, including meteorology, education, and science policy. Includes both finished speeches, rough notes, and background material. Also includes notes on lectures in meteorology given at SFU.
  - Speeches, 1946; F-65-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-17)
  - Speeches, 1946 - 1963; F-65-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-17)
  - Speeches, 1964; F-65-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-17)
  - Speeches - speech material, 1964 - 1965; F-65-5-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-17)
  - Speeches, 1965 - 1966; F-65-5-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speech material, 1966 - 1967; F-65-5-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - SFU BISC 300 Lecture notes, 1967; F-65-5-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches, 1968; F-65-5-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches, 1968 - 1969; F-65-5-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches, 1968 - 1975; F-65-5-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches - Canadian Meteorological Society, 1969; F-65-5-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches, 1970 - 1971; F-65-5-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches - Canadian Meteorological Service -- Symposium, 1971; F-65-5-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches 1/2, 1972; F-65-5-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 65-18)
  - Speeches 2/2, 1972; F-65-5-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 65-19)
  - Speeches, 1973; F-65-5-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 65-19)
  - Speeches 1/2, 1974; F-65-5-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 65-19)
  - Speeches 2/2, 1974; F-65-5-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 65-19)
  - Speeches, 1974 - 1975; F-65-5-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 65-19)
  - Speeches 1/2, 1977; F-65-5-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 65-19)
  - Speeches 2/2, 1977; F-65-5-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 65-19)
  - Speeches, 1978 - 1996; F-65-5-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 65-20)
- Publications, 1934 - 1996; F-65-6; 6 cm of textual records
  Series consists of publications written or collected by McTaggart-Cowan. Includes articles by McTaggart-Cowan, newspaper clippings, and publications and reports about the oil spill at Chedabucto Bay.
  - Articles by McTaggart-Cowan, 1938 - 1974; F-65-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-20)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1934 - 1996; F-65-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-20)
- Photographs, 1930 - 1985; F-65-7; 19 cm of textual records ca. 350 photographs
  Series consists of photographs produced throughout Patrick McTaggart-Cowan's personal and professional life. Includes photographs of family, school days, portraits, Gander airport, conferences, SFU, and others.
  - Family photographs, 1933 - 1944; F-65-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Family and Oxford - copy negatives, 1930 - 1939; F-65-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Family photographs, 1960 - 1969; F-65-7-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Portraits and publicity photographs, 1944 - [ca 1979]; F-65-7-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Portraits - negative, 1963; F-65-7-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Botwood, Newfoundland, 1937 - 1939; F-65-7-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Gander airport, Newfoundland 1/2, 1939 - 1942; F-65-7-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Gander airport, Newfoundland 2/2, 1939 - 1942; F-65-7-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - North Atlantic Route Service Conference, 1946; F-65-7-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Meteorological conferences and events, 1947 - 1962; F-65-7-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Facsimile inauguration / weather fax system, 1953; F-65-7-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Commission on Synoptic Meteorology - World Meteorological Conference, Washington, 1953; F-65-7-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Meteorological Conference, 1953; F-65-7-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Honourary degrees, 1961 - 1974; F-65-7-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Dinner in honour of P.D. McTaggart-Cowan in recognition of his career with the Meteorological Service of Canada, 1964; F-65-7-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - SFU photographs, 1963 - 1968; F-65-7-0-0-16 (Archival box - small 65-29)
  - SFU, 1964 - 1968; F-65-7-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - SFU opening, 1965; F-65-7-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - SFU, 1972 - 1985; F-65-7-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 65-21)
  - Science Council, 1970 - 1979; F-65-7-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 65-21)